# Chebesi EdyLionel Awah

## Full Stack Developer (MERN)

Douala Cameroon chebesiawah@gmail.com +237 6 77 97 21 26

I am a Self taught freelance developer who learned how to build high performance web and mobile apps by watching videos on Udemy and YouTube since 2019. Over the past years, I have ameliorated my skills while working on diverse projects from clients across different parts of the world.

I am specialized in projects using MERN stack, because I just love MERN.

- I am a good team worker,
- Attentive to details,
- · Quick to learn,
- And I love challenges

I love sports, particularly football, am interested in world politics, dancing and taking walks.

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

Sponsorship required to work in the US

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

Sponsorship required to work in the US

# Work Experience

## **Front End Developer**

Icemix.net - Douala December 2021 to July 2022

Worked on the User interface of their project currently in development. We built the frontend using Vue js and Bootstrap

#### **Front End Developer**

Virtual Pro Gaming - Mason, OH September 2021 to November 2021

I worked on a project that used React Js and Typescript. Using React Query, I had to interact with the server, getting data from the back and displaying it on the client side. I also updated the User Interface of the client side using libraries like Materia UI.

#### Front End Web Developer

Silver Line Startup - Douala January 2021 to August 2021

Developed User Interfaces using HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript and React Js . I also had tasks that involved fetching data from the server using APIs. Aided the team in updating company's website as well as redesigned user experience for websites

#### **Full Stack Developer**

BEWOCA NGO - Bamenda January 2020 to December 2020 I built and managed their Web application for the NGO using React, Node and MSQL.

# Education

# **Diploma in Full Stack Developer**

Udemy - Remote

January 2019 to Present

## **B.A.** in Law and Public Administration

University of Yaounde 2 Soa - Yaounde, CM October 2011 to August 2014

# Skills

- HTML5
- MongoDB
- TypeScript
- Bootstrap
- Vue.js
- React Native
- Express.js
- MySQL
- JavaScript
- CSS
- Node.js
- React js
- Firebase
- Material UI
- English
- Fluent
- French
- Intermediate
- Spanish
- Beginner

## Links

https://chebsportfolio.netlify.app

https://www.linkedin.com/in/chebesi-awah-b891331ab

# Certifications and Licenses

# FreeCodeCamp JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures

May 2022 to June 2022

Licenses & certifications freeCodeCamp
JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures
Issued Jun 2022 ·
No Expiration Date Credential ID fccd9ff51ad-ee2b-49ac-bdb2-422d3b15a5c2